Inventory of the Ed Zschau papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Ed Zschau papers
1982-1987
86046
Zschau, Ed, 1940-
193 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 3 computer tape reels (81.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, memoranda, press releases, bills, testimony, studies, campaign literature, printed matter, and video tapes, relating to Congressional election campaigns, and various national political issues, particularly export administration of high technology products.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1986.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Zschau has an A.B. degree from Princeton University and M.B.A., M.S., and Ph.D. degrees from Stanford University. He was founder and CEO of System Industries from 1968 through 1981. In 1982 Zschau was elected to the U.S. House of Representatives and represented the Silicon Valley area in Congress for two terms, ending in 1986. In 1987 he became a General Partner of Brentwood Associates, a venture capital firm, and in 1988 was elected Chairman and CEO of Censtor Corp., a position held until he became General Manager of the IBM Storage Systems Division from 1993 to 1995. He is currently the chairman of Princeton Power Systems, Inc., StarTek, Inc., co-founder and chairman of Polyera Corporation, and director of WashingtonLive, Inc. and Chisholm, Inc. He currently teaches in the electrical engineering department at Princeton University.
Source: American Action Forum, http://americanactionforum.org/experts/ed-zschau
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection contains correspondence, memoranda, press releases, bills, testimony, studies, campaign literature, printed matter, and video tapes, relating to Congressional election campaigns, and various national political issues, particularly export administration of high technology products.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
United States. Congress. House.; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); United States. Politics and government, 1981-1989.; Export controls--United States.; High technology industries--United States.; California--Politics and government--1951-; Statesmen--United States.
Collection Contents
- High technology (Folder 1-5)
- 1986 Senatorial campaign (Folder 6-9)
- High technology (Folder 9)
- Mail reports (Folder 10)
- 1986 campaign (Folder 11)
- Mail reports (Folder 12)
- 1986 campaign video tapes (Folder 12-16)
- 1986 campaign tapes (Folder 17)
- Computer disks (Folder 17)
- Poll result printout (Folder 18)
- Correspondence, 1986 May 26-July 17 (Folder 19-21)
- Floor statements by Zschau (Folder 22-23)
- Export administration (Folder 24-26)
- Correspondence, 1986 April 2-May 23 (Folder 27-30)
- Correspondence, 1986 January 22-April 3 (Folder 30-33)
- Correspondence, 1986 September 23-December 9 (Folder 34-37)
- Correspondence, 1986 December 1-1986 January 21 (Folder 37-40)
- Task force hearings, 1984 July 31-August 1 (Folder 41-43)
  Includes 1986 trade bill
- Bills sponsored and co-sponsored by Zschau (Folder 44-46)
- Miscellaneous cases and issues (Folder 46-49)
- Tax policy (Folder 49-52)
- Research and development (Folder 49-52)
- Capital gains (Folder 49-52)
- Cost of capital (Folder 49-52)
- Environment (Folder 52-54)
- Agriculture (Folder 52-54)
- Foreign affairs (Folder 55-57)
- Defense (Folder 55-57)
- Budget (Folder 57-60)
- Miscellaneous high technology (Folder 57-60)
- Press releases (Folder 60-63)
- Testimony (Folder 60-63)
- Articles (Folder 60-63)
- Foreign affairs (Folder 63-65)
- Defense (Folder 63-65)
- High Technology Task Force (Folder 66-69)
- Closed cases (Folder 69-72)
- Newsletters (Folder 72-75)
- Questionnaires (Folder 72-75)
- Co-signed letters (Folder 72-75)
- Export administration (Folder 75-77)
- High technology (Folder 75-77)
- Press clippings regarding Zschau (Folder 77-81)
- Form letter replies (Folder 77-81)
- Correspondence, 1986 July 18-September 19 (Folder 82-84)
- Press clippings regarding Zschau (Folder 85-86)
- Press releases (Folder 86-88)
- Weekly columns (Folder 86-88)
- "Dear colleagues" letters (Folder 86-88)
- Interns (Folder 88-91)
- Constituents (Folder 88-91)
- Photographs (Folder 88-91)
- Foreign affairs (Folder 91-96)
- Defense (Folder 91-96)
- Administrative (Folder 97-99)
- Committees (Folder 97-99)
- Departmental (Folder 97-99)
- High technology (Folder 100-102)
- Export Administration Act (Folder 100-102)
- Correspondence, 1983 (Folder 102-111)
- Cases (Folder 111-114)
- Correspondence, 1983 (Folder 114-116)
- Correspondence, 1985 January-February (Folder 117-120)
- Cases (Folder 120-125)
- Correspondence, 1984 January 1-February 21 (Folder 125-128)
- Correspondence, 1985 September 21-October 31 (Folder 128-131)
- 1983 legislation, E-F (Folder 132-135)
- Correspondence, 1985 March 1-April 3 (Folder 135-138)
- 1983 legislation, A-D (Folder 139-142)
- 1983 legislation, D-E (Folder 142-145)
- 1983 legislation, E (Folder 145-148)
- Correspondence, 1984 February 22-March 31 (Folder 148-151)
- Correspondence, 1984 May 10-June 20 (Folder 152-154)
- Correspondence, 1984 June 20-July 31 (Folder 154-157)
- Correspondence, 1984 August 1-September 19 (Folder 157-160)
- Correspondence, 1984 November 1-December 31 (Folder 160-163)
- 1983 legislation, H-R (Folder 163-166)
- 1983 legislation, S-Z (Folder 166-169)
- Correspondence, 1985 November 1-December 31 (Folder 169-172)
- Correspondence, 1984 September 20-October 31 (Folder 172-174)
- Correspondence, 1985 April 4-30 (Folder 175-177)
- 1983 legislation, F-L (Folder 177-180)
- Correspondence, 1985 May 1-June 10 (Folder 180-183)
- Correspondence, 1984 April 1-May 9 (Folder 183-186)
- Correspondence, 1985 June 10-July 31 (Folder 186-189)
- Correspondence, 1985 August 1-September 20 (Folder 189-192)
- Clippings regarding Zschau, 1983-1984 (Folder 193-194)
- 3 computer tape reels of data from correspondence and other files (Folder Tape Cabinet)